<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Between Books</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/atom.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/atom.xml</id>
    <author>
        <name>Noon van der Silk</name>
        <email>noonsilk+-noonsilk@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
    <updated>2023-08-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <entry>
    <title>My Work</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/my-work-2020.html" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/my-work-2020.html</id>
    <published>2023-08-27T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-08-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Really an exceptional piece of writing. A friend bought this for me,
and at the time I didn't realise I had already read another of her
books. This one is of a totally different character; basically telling
the story of a woman's engagement with pregnancy, and the way society
encourages it be handled. Being myself now a partner and a witness to
this, I found it a very interesting perspective and helped me relate to
the birth parent more. It's a stressful read, but an amazing one I
think. Highly recommended!</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>The Joyful Environmentalist: How to Practise without Preaching</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/the-joyful-environmentalist-2020.html" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/the-joyful-environmentalist-2020.html</id>
    <published>2023-08-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-08-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I quite enjoyed this book; but it's probably not for everyone. Losada
has an engaging and friendly style; extremely readable and enjoyable.
The way she engages with the topic is pretty generous I think; perhaps
the main criticism is that it's occasionally a bit too optimistic; but
after all, that's basically what it promises on the cover! Overall, if
you're looking for a bit of optimism and happiness, then take a glance!
I'll definitely be trying to read more of her books :)</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>The Snakehead</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/the-snakehead-2009.html" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/the-snakehead-2009.html</id>
    <published>2023-07-24T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-07-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I picked this up because I've quite enjoyed his other books. This one
was also pretty good; certainly compelling and readable. That said, it
doesn't particularly challenge ideas about borders or immigration in any
way that I would find agreeable. There's no doubt Keefe is a great
story-teller, and I did enjoy reading this one, but you could be
forgiven for passing it up for something else. That said, it did at
least highlight to me <em>some</em> of the challenges building an
effective immigration policy.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Rental Person Who Does Nothing: A Memoir</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/rental-person-who-does-nothing-2023.html" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/rental-person-who-does-nothing-2023.html</id>
    <published>2023-07-09T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-07-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a strange one. I didn't know anything about this person or
service, and I was expecting the book to be mostly funny. But it was
actually far more serious and thoughtful than I had anticipated. I
probably wouldn't recommend it to everyone; but it's at least refreshing
for it's alternative take on what it means to live and relate to people.
I also found it, I think, to be an interesting insight into some parts
of modern Japanese culture. Quirky, for sure, a little depressing, even,
but a worthwhile read nevertheless.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>The Roads to Sata: A 2000-Mile Walk Through Japan</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/the-roads-to-sata-1985.html" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/the-roads-to-sata-1985.html</id>
    <published>2023-06-20T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Extremely readable and enjoyable. Booth managed to write in such a
way that the atmosphere of the journey and the places was very well
conveyed. Made me want to be there! Just some really nice story-telling.
Highly recommended :)</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Regenesis: Feeding the World Without Devouring the Planet</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/regenesis-2022.html" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/regenesis-2022.html</id>
    <published>2023-05-21T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Amazing reading, ideas, and suggested actions for wildly revising how
food is produced. I found this book particularly relevant because I have
just started a new job that is in this space; but even otherwise it is a
great, non-judgemental, and surprisingly inspiring, book about the
climate crisis. It may even inspire you to start gardening :)</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Banzeiro Òkòtó: The Amazon as the Center of the World</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/banzeiro-%C3%B2k%C3%B2t%C3%B3-2023.html" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/banzeiro-%C3%B2k%C3%B2t%C3%B3-2023.html</id>
    <published>2023-05-14T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Absolutely extraordinary book. Extremely informative, powerful,
emotional, inspiring, and poetic. I was struck at first by the amazing
writing (which comes across really well in translation, I think, not
that I've read the original ...), but stayed for the amazing
story-telling and information about various illegal practices in
Brazil.</p>
<p>It's really an impressive piece of work, I can highly recommend it,
but do note that it is also, in parts, quite traumatic. Still; one of
those books that you feel sad when it ends; well worth reading!</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>The Candy House</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/the-candy-house-2022.html" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/the-candy-house-2022.html</id>
    <published>2023-05-07T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An enjoyably rich read. I can't quite say what I got out of this
other than simply the joy of reading. One thing I know for sure is that
Egan is an amazing writer. I was reading this and another book, at the
same time, and it was just incomparable how good her writing was ... in
comparision :D. One memorable moment is that I read a lot of this book
aloud, and the part where she writes as a teenager is just, for my mind,
absolutely spot on. Anyway; highly recommend this one for some relaxing
reading!</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>No-Drama Discipline: The Whole-Brain Way to Calm the Chaos and Nurture Your Child's Developing Mind</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/no-drama-discipline-2014.html" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/no-drama-discipline-2014.html</id>
    <published>2023-04-30T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I liked this book. It discusses what seem to be some quite reasonable
approaches for dealing with children. It's a bit too early for me to put
in to practice, but a lot of the discussions seem quite good, and it'll
probably be something I refer back to in a few years :)</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Tokyo Vice: An American Reporter on the Police Beat in Japan</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/tokyo-vice-2009.html" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/tokyo-vice-2009.html</id>
    <published>2023-04-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I picked this up after watching and enjoying the show. The book is
quite different; and it's interesting actually to compare it with the
show; the team that converted the book into the show have done an
impressive job, I think! I like both. I really couldn't put the book
down. It has compellingly written and just interesting. A great read for
those interested in the workings of organised crime (and journalism!) in
Japan. I loved it!</p>]]></summary>
</entry>

</feed>
