<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Between Books</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/atom.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/atom.xml</id>
    <author>
        <name>Noon van der Silk</name>
        <email>noonsilk+-noonsilk@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
    <updated>2023-04-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <entry>
    <title>No-Drama Discipline: The Whole-Brain Way to Calm the Chaos and Nurture Your Child's Developing Mind</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/no-drama-discipline-2014.html" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/no-drama-discipline-2014.html</id>
    <published>2023-04-30T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I liked this book. It discusses what seem to be some quite reasonable
approaches for dealing with children. It's a bit too early for me to put
in to practice, but a lot of the discussions seem quite good, and it'll
probably be something I refer back to in a few years :)</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Tokyo Vice: An American Reporter on the Police Beat in Japan</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/tokyo-vice-2009.html" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/tokyo-vice-2009.html</id>
    <published>2023-04-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I picked this up after watching and enjoying the show. The book is
quite different; and it's interesting actually to compare it with the
show; the team that converted the book into the show have done an
impressive job, I think! I like both. I really couldn't put the book
down. It has compellingly written and just interesting. A great read for
those interested in the workings of organised crime (and journalism!) in
Japan. I loved it!</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>The World We Make</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/the-world-we-make-2022.html" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/the-world-we-make-2022.html</id>
    <published>2023-04-16T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Not bad; just not mind-blowing like the rest of her work. She's set
an extremely high bar for her work, and while this series is good for
anyone else, for me it was just a bit lacking the brilliance of her
earlier ones. But it's a bit of an unfair comparision. Her first few
books were, for me, just absolutely amazing, and this series didn't
quite compare. It's still good, and worth reading all the way to the end
of the acknowledgements for an alternative title. But if you were
compelled to read only one of her works, you would start with literally
any other series.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Feminism, Interrupted: Disrupting Power</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/feminism%2C-interrupted-2020.html" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/feminism%2C-interrupted-2020.html</id>
    <published>2023-04-03T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-04-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Really a brilliant collection of insights and strong thoughts around
feminism and it's connections to all aspects of society and life. The
book is short but somehow packed with some much knowledge and beautiful
connections to other works and writers/thinkers. Lola is a genius,
really, of explaining practical ways to engage with feminism, and what
it means for how we can engage it to bring about change. If you're ever
at a loss for words when someone asks you "What is feminism?" then this
book is for you!</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Strong Female Character</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/strong-female-character-2023.html" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/strong-female-character-2023.html</id>
    <published>2023-03-24T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-03-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Really quite interesting and good. I think I'd seen Fern Brady
before, and she's clearly and interesting person, but this an
enlightening book for me, in particular in building some empathy for how
people with autism experience life and their emotions, and in particular
women. Great reading!</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>The Complete Persepolis</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/persepolis-2003.html" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/persepolis-2003.html</id>
    <published>2023-02-19T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-02-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've got mixed feelings about this book. Mostly, it was good; it was informative and I learned a lot. The graphic novel form is also just a nice way to convey a complicated topic with lots of personal feeling and information. On the other hand, I can't say I found the author totally likeable; but perhaps that just means she presented her story truly; after all, we all make mistakes and say things we regret. In any case, I'm glad I read this, and if you're at all curious about a personal perspective on Iran, I at least found it interesting and worthwhile.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Small Things Like These</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/small-things-like-these-2021.html" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/small-things-like-these-2021.html</id>
    <published>2023-02-05T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-02-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Loved this one. It's indeed beautifully written; extremely readable and interesting. It has a softness, and I really enjoyed my time with this one :) Also nice to learn some Irish words and culture!</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Everyone in This Room Will Someday Be Dead</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/everyone-in-this-room-will-someday-be-dead-2021.html" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/everyone-in-this-room-will-someday-be-dead-2021.html</id>
    <published>2023-01-29T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hilarious and brilliant. Very enjoyable reading; only note is that at the time I was reading this I was occasionally visiting a hospital, and I had to hide the cover :)</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>How to Blow Up a Pipeline</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/how-to-blow-up-a-pipeline-2021.html" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/how-to-blow-up-a-pipeline-2021.html</id>
    <published>2023-01-15T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I quite liked this. It's a nice discussion of climate activism and the general connection between activism and resistance. It leaves a lot of food for thought about what is necessary in order to make people change their behaviours. A great, short, thoughtful, and inspiring read.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Once Upon a Tome: The Misadventures of a Rare Bookseller</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/once-upon-a-tome-2022.html" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/once-upon-a-tome-2022.html</id>
    <published>2023-01-08T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-01-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just simply an extremely enjoyable and engaging read about life in a bookshop :) I loved it; I've been reading a few of these "real-life bookshop" stories, to get a sense of what it might be like to work in one, and I think this story is particularly interesting because of the history associated with this particular bookshop, and of course the author is just a great story teller. Highly recommended if you want to get a sense of the magic that it could be, to work in a rare bookshop!</p>]]></summary>
</entry>

</feed>
