<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Between Books</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/atom.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/atom.xml</id>
    <author>
        <name>Noon van der Silk</name>
        <email>noonsilk+-noonsilk@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
    <updated>2024-06-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <entry>
    <title>Venice: City of Pictures</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2024/venice%3A-city-of-pictures-2023.html" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2024/venice%3A-city-of-pictures-2023.html</id>
    <published>2024-06-02T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2024-06-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I loved this. I haven't read much art history, but this was a
beautiful way to learn to appreciate art in the context in which it was
made. Also contained some nice detours into architecture and urban
planning that influenced the art/development of Venice. Will definitely
try and read more like this in the future!</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>The Cabin in the Mountains: A Norwegian Odyssey</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2024/the-cabin-in-the-mountains-2019.html" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2024/the-cabin-in-the-mountains-2019.html</id>
    <published>2024-04-07T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2024-04-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Simple, funny, enjoyable, and atmospheric. Really just a nice story
of someone embedding themselves in a foreign culture. I really enjoyed
it :)</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>The Woman in Me</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/the-woman-in-me-2023.html" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/the-woman-in-me-2023.html</id>
    <published>2023-11-05T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-11-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was interesting and sad, truthfully. I've read a few of these
"high-profile female celebrity" life books, and the common theme is just
how much of a "normal" life they want, and how people around them betray
them. I also think it's such a shame for people who's professional dream
just happens to be one which makes them famous (not something that is
likely to happen to me!), and then they suffer the consequences.</p>
<p>Of course there is also the story of the conservatorship, which
personally I can't begin to understand how it's legal.</p>
<p>Overall, a very interesting and worthwhile read, and just a reminder,
for me, of the importance of building self-empowerment in all children,
and just the appreciation for a caring and supportive upbringing that I
have had.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Sherpa: Stories of Life and Death from the Forgotten Guardians of Everest</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/sherpa-2022.html" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/sherpa-2022.html</id>
    <published>2023-09-17T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-09-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I learned a lot from this book. I quite enjoyed how it covered a
variety of experiences of people from the Sherpa community, and it seems
to me that it did a pretty fair job. It's certainly interesting to see
how the Sherpa's view climbing. Worth a read for the stories and if
you're interested in climbing culture and how and why the Sherpa's
participate.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>My Work</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/my-work-2020.html" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/my-work-2020.html</id>
    <published>2023-08-27T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-08-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Really an exceptional piece of writing. A friend bought this for me,
and at the time I didn't realise I had already read another of her
books. This one is of a totally different character; basically telling
the story of a woman's engagement with pregnancy, and the way society
encourages it be handled. Being myself now a partner and a witness to
this, I found it a very interesting perspective and helped me relate to
the birth parent more. It's a stressful read, but an amazing one I
think. Highly recommended!</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>The Joyful Environmentalist: How to Practise without Preaching</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/the-joyful-environmentalist-2020.html" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/the-joyful-environmentalist-2020.html</id>
    <published>2023-08-23T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-08-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I quite enjoyed this book; but it's probably not for everyone. Losada
has an engaging and friendly style; extremely readable and enjoyable.
The way she engages with the topic is pretty generous I think; perhaps
the main criticism is that it's occasionally a bit too optimistic; but
after all, that's basically what it promises on the cover! Overall, if
you're looking for a bit of optimism and happiness, then take a glance!
I'll definitely be trying to read more of her books :)</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>The Snakehead</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/the-snakehead-2009.html" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/the-snakehead-2009.html</id>
    <published>2023-07-24T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-07-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I picked this up because I've quite enjoyed his other books. This one
was also pretty good; certainly compelling and readable. That said, it
doesn't particularly challenge ideas about borders or immigration in any
way that I would find agreeable. There's no doubt Keefe is a great
story-teller, and I did enjoy reading this one, but you could be
forgiven for passing it up for something else. That said, it did at
least highlight to me <em>some</em> of the challenges building an
effective immigration policy.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Rental Person Who Does Nothing: A Memoir</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/rental-person-who-does-nothing-2023.html" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/rental-person-who-does-nothing-2023.html</id>
    <published>2023-07-09T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-07-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a strange one. I didn't know anything about this person or
service, and I was expecting the book to be mostly funny. But it was
actually far more serious and thoughtful than I had anticipated. I
probably wouldn't recommend it to everyone; but it's at least refreshing
for it's alternative take on what it means to live and relate to people.
I also found it, I think, to be an interesting insight into some parts
of modern Japanese culture. Quirky, for sure, a little depressing, even,
but a worthwhile read nevertheless.</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>The Roads to Sata: A 2000-Mile Walk Through Japan</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/the-roads-to-sata-1985.html" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/the-roads-to-sata-1985.html</id>
    <published>2023-06-20T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-06-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Extremely readable and enjoyable. Booth managed to write in such a
way that the atmosphere of the journey and the places was very well
conveyed. Made me want to be there! Just some really nice story-telling.
Highly recommended :)</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Regenesis: Feeding the World Without Devouring the Planet</title>
    <link href="https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/regenesis-2022.html" />
    <id>https://betweenbooks.com.au/updates/2023/regenesis-2022.html</id>
    <published>2023-05-21T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2023-05-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Amazing reading, ideas, and suggested actions for wildly revising how
food is produced. I found this book particularly relevant because I have
just started a new job that is in this space; but even otherwise it is a
great, non-judgemental, and surprisingly inspiring, book about the
climate crisis. It may even inspire you to start gardening :)</p>]]></summary>
</entry>

</feed>
